11018 27<sup>th</sup> AVE NE (916)280-3229 Seattle, WA, 98125

phamqalanq@qmail.com

Portfolio: <a href="https://www.glenrage.com">www.glenrage.com</a> Github: <a href="https://github.com/glenrage">github.com/glenrage</a>

## **GALANG** (Glen)

## **PHAM**

"I am passionate and prideful about my work no matter the job or task and believe expectations are meant to be exceeded."

#### **SUMMARY**

Driven professional with broad technical and soft skill sets who thrives in fast paced environments. 8 years of military experience has instilled leadership, communication, teamwork, and tenacity. Known for ability to meet deadlines and translate ideas into testable readable and reliable code.

#### **WEB DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS**

## **Equi-Gallery-VR** Full Stack Application

github.com/glenrage/Equi-Gallery-VR

Lead developer in creating full stack application with Mongo, Node, Express, Angular, Passport, and AframelO. It allows photographers to create a personalized gallery to upload Equi-Rectangular photos and view them in virtual reality with VR supported devices.

### **Effort-Manager** Back End Server Application

github.com/CF-8-week-challenge/effort-manager

Lead developer in creating back end server for an iOS development team for a fitness app that tracks daily challenges. RESTful API built with Mongo, Node, Express. 90% test coverage and features full CRUD operations.

#### RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

## Oct 2016 - Present Full Stack Web Developer

Self Taught / Code Fellows, Seattle, WA

Learned Advanced Software Development in Javascript. Implemented industry's best practices in writing quality, maintainable code and development processes. Integrated data through back end services and frameworks.

## 2006 - 2014 U.S Air Force (Supervisor, Data Analyst)

McChord AFB, WA, Worldwide multiple

Led and supervised aircraft maintenance teams on multiple deployments to hazardous combat zones. Managed planning and development of maintenance metrics reports. Performed maintenance data analysis to efficiently reduce unnecessary maintenance tasks by 20%.

#### **EDUCATION**

Feb-June 2017 Full Stack Web Development Intensive

Code Fellows

2009-2013 Bachelor of Science in Technical Management

Embry - Riddle Aeronautical University - Daytona Beach, FL

# PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

JavaScript/jQuery HTML5/CSS/SASS

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

### Core

Object Oriented/
Functional Programming
MVC
RESTful API
Continuous Integration
Test/Behavior Driven
Development
Debugging
Documentation

#### **Frameworks**

Angular

React

**Express** 

Node

MongoDB

**Passport** 

PostgresSQL

BootStrap

Redux

#### **Testing Frameworks**

Mocha/Chai Jasmine/Karma

### Systems/Tools

Microsoft Windows Mac OSX Git version control AWS Webpack

## SPOKEN Languages

English (Proficient)
Vietnamese (Proficient)